Finding Aid to the Jane Dupree Richardson papers SSC.MS.00208
Sophia Smith Collection
Jane Dupree Richardson papers
1768-2010
Sophia Smith Collection
Richardson, Jane DuPree
SSC.MS.00208
68.75 linear feet (56 boxes.)
Jane Dupree Richardson is a free-lance writer, editor, translator, and editor/publisher of "Annotated Bibliography of Published Women's Diaries" in 1977 and of "Women's Diaries, a Quarterly Newsletter." The collection consist of personal and professional papers of Richardson, including diaries (original and photocopies) and financial and business material related to her "Women's Diaries Newsletter." The collection contains two boxes of diaries by socialite and traveler Katrin Vietor.
Conditions Governing Access
Journals and personal correspondence dated after Sept 1, 1957 are to be closed until Jan 1, 2050 or during the lifetimes of her children, whichever comes first. "These materials can be consulted only with the written consent of my children."
Conditions Governing Access
Closed until processed.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by Jane DuPree Richardson. Accession numbers: 99S-18, 00S-29, 06S-33, 07S-52, 11S-06, 13S-54. Accessions were received on the following dates: 1999, 2000-06-30, 2006-05-31, 2007-08-06, 2011-02-04, 2013-09-13.
Biographical Note
Jane Dupree Richardson was born December 14, 1930. She received her B.A. in modern languages from the University of Georgia in 1951 and an M.A. in French from Columbia University in 1965. She served in the United States Naval Reserve, (1952-57), working with the Office of Naval Intelligence (1952-54), and NATO (1955-57). She self published "Annotated Bibliography of Published Women's Diaries" in 1977 and was editor/publisher of "Women's Diaries, a Quarterly Newsletter." Richardson is also a free-lance writer, editor and translator.
Related Materials
Richardson's collection of published diaries (of men and women) were donated to University of Georgia Libraries, and her collection of women artists'diaries to the National Museum of Women in the Arts.
Scope and Contents
The Jane Dupree Richardson Papers consist of the personal papers of Richardson and her family. They also include the professional papers of Richardson, including diaries (original and photocopies) and financial and business material related to her "Women's Diaries Newsletter." The collection contains two boxes of diaries by socialite and traveler Katrin Vietor. Only the most recent accessions are listed in this finding aid.
Diaries-authorship; Richardson, Jane Dupree, 1930-; Women in the professions--United States--History--20th century--Sources; correspondence; diaries; Financial records; Slides; photographs; memorabilia; Calendars; Richardson, Jane Dupree; Richardson, Jane DuPree; Richardson, Jane DuPree
- Jane Dupree Richardson's correspondence, materials pertaining to Amish community and 2006 Pennsylvania schoolhouse shootings, 1979-2006; 2007-S-0052; Richardson, Jane Dupree; 1.25 linear feet (1 box)
  Richardson, Jane Dupree
  - Correspondence, emails, 1998-2005; 2007-S-0052 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper, magazines regarding schoolhouse shootings, 2004-2006; 2007-S-0052 (Box 1)
  - M.A. thesis: "Love and Suffering in the Novels of Julien Greene", undated; 2007-S-0052 (Box 1)
  - Appointment books, 1999-2005; 2007-S-0052 (Box 1)
  - Academic notes, 1979-1981; 2007-S-0052 (Box 1)
  - Business cards, 1980-2002; 2007-S-0052 (Box 1)
- Jane Dupree Richardson's correspondence and diaries, 1975-2010; 2011-S-0006; Richardson, Jane Dupree; 1.25 linear feet (1 box)
  - Biographical and publicity materials, 1980-1999; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject files: Marimekko textiles, 2002-2007; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject files: notary public, 1998-2006; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: Pere Marquette portrait, 2010; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: Dutchess County Historical Society, 1992; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: Northumberland County Historical Society, 1992-2004; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: Packwood House Museum, 2005-2006; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: children, 2006-2008; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: family, 2006; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: friends, 2006-2009; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: "Lunch Bunch", 2006-2009; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: Valeria Harms, 2008; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file; Peat O'Neil, 1987-2010; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Subject file: Mary Ann Wren, 2006-2008; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous materials: publication lists, advertisements, general, undated; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
  - Calendars, diaries, 1975-2006; 2011-S-0006 (Box 1)
- Jane Dupree Richardson: correspondence, calendar, photographs, publication, 1976-2012; 2013-S-0054; Richardson, Jane Dupree; 1.25 linear feet
  - Correspondence, mostly personal, 1976-2012; 2013-S-0054 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 2000; undated; 2013-S-0054 (Box 2)
  - VHS tape: Mahantango Valley Quilt Exhibit, 2000; 2013-S-0054 (Box 2)
  - Calendar, 2011; 2013-S-0054 (Box 2)
  - Notebooks, 1970-1989; 2013-S-0054 (Box 2)
  - "Diary of a Young Woman of Scott County, Indiana," by Carrie Kimberlin; transcribed, annotated by Jane Dupree Richardson, 2011; 2013-S-0054 (Box 2)